Renaissance architecture photograph collection (Africa-Denmark)
Yale University Arts Library
Renaissance architecture photograph collection (Africa-Denmark)
1900-2005
VRC 34.1
Yale University Arts Library
6.66
16 boxes (Boxes 1-16 of 136)
Collection consists of black and white and color reproductions of Renaissance architecture. Section I includes Africa-Denmark. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by country. Further sub-divided by location, building type, and building name.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white and color reproductions of Renaissance architecture. Section I includes Africa-Denmark. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Architecture, Renaissance; Photographs; Reproductions
- Architecture: Renaissance Part I. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Africa., 5 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 5 (Box 1)
      - Cape Province, Drakenstein Valley, South Africa., 2 (Box 1)
      - Luanda., 2 (Box 1)
      - Muxima., 1 (Box 1)
  - Austria., 80 (Box 1)
    - Pictures of and by J. B. Fisher von Erlach., 3 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 10 (Box 1)
      - Gleink., 1 (Box 1)
      - Graz., 1 (Box 1)
      - Klosterneuburg., 1 (Box 1)
      - Kremsier., 1 (Box 1)
      - Linz., 1 (Box 1)
      - Melk., 3 (Box 1)
      - Stams., 1 (Box 1)
      - Zwettl., 1 (Box 1)
    - Individual locations., 67 (Box 1)
      - Innsbruck., 7 (Box 1)
      - Salzburg., 12 (Box 1)
      - Vienna., 48 (Box 1)
        - Miscellaneous buildings, views, and sketches., 32 (Box 1)
        - Belvedere Palace., 7 (Box 1)
        - Schonbrunn Palace., 9 (Box 1)
  - Belgium., 32 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 6 (Box 1)
      - Arras., 1 (Box 1)
      - Beloeil., 1 (Box 1)
      - Ghent., 1 (Box 1)
      - Laken., 1 (Box 1)
      - Seneffe., 1 (Box 1)
      - Tournai., 1 (Box 1)
    - Individual locations., 26 (Box 1)
      - Antwerp (Anvers)., 13 (Box 1)
        - Miscellaneous buildings and views., 7 (Box 1)
        - Musee Plantin., 6 (Box 1)
      - Bruges., 6 (Box 1)
      - Brussels., 7 (Box 2)
  - Britain., 963 (Box 2)
    Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
    - General information, gardens and architectural details., 11 (Box 2)
    - Architectural ornament., 29 (Box 2)
      - Elizabethan., 2 (Box 2)
      - Jacobean., 6 (Box 2)
      - William and Mary., 4 (Box 2)
      - Georgian., 13 (Box 2)
      - Adam., 4 (Box 2)
    - General architects., 30 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous architects., 12 (Box 2)
        - Unknown., 1 (Box 2)
        - Adam brothers., 1 (Box 2)
        - Adam, Robert., 1 (Box 2)
        - Gibbs, James., 1 (Box 2)
        - Hamilton, David, 1768-1843., 3 (Box 2)
        - Hawksmoor, Nicholas., 1 (Box 2)
        - Hope, Thomas, c.1769-1831., 1 (Box 2)
        - Kent, William, 1684-1748., 1 (Box 2)
        - Webb, John, 1611-1672., 1 (Box 2)
        - Wren, Christopher, 1632-1723., 1 (Box 2)
      - Individual architects., 18 (Box 2)
        - Jones, Inigo, 1573-1652., 15 (Box 2)
        - Langley, Batty, 1696-1751., 3 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 163 (Box 3)
      Includes three folders of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Abingdon., 1 (Box 3)
      - Alnwich, Northumberland., 1 (Box 3)
      - Althorp, Northamptonshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Ashby, Castle., 1 (Box 3)
      - Audley End, Essex., 1 (Box 3)
      - Badminton House., 2 (Box 3)
      - Bakewell., 1 (Box 3)
      - Barrington Court, Somerset., 1 (Box 3)
      - Blackheath., 1 (Box 3)
      - Bolsover Castle, Chesterfield, Derby., 1 (Box 3)
      - Bradford-on-Avon, Wiltshire., 2 (Box 3)
      - Bramshill, Hampshire., 2 (Box 3)
      - Brereton Hall, Cheshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Brighton., 1 (Box 3)
      - Bristol., 2 (Box 3)
      - Broome Park, Kent., 1 (Box 3)
      - Broughton., 1 (Box 3)
      - Burton Agnes, Yorkshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Buscot Park., 1 (Box 3)
      - Camden, Gloustershire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Cannons Park., 1 (Box 3)
      - Castle Blunden, County Kilkenny, Ireland., 1 (Box 3)
      - Castle Campbell, near Dollar Glen., 1 (Box 3)
      - Castle Coole, Fermanagh Co., 2 (Box 3)
      - Castle Fraser, Aberdeenshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Castletown., 2 (Box 3)
      - Castleward., 2 (Box 3)
      - Charney Bassett Manor, Berkshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Charlton House, Kent, Wiltshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Chastleton, Oxford., 2 (Box 3)
      - Chelvey Court., 1 (Box 3)
      - Chilham, Kent., 1 (Box 3)
      - Chipping Camden, Gloucestershire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Clytha Castle, Wales., 2 (Box 3)
      - Coleshill., 1 (Box 3)
      - Compton Wynates, Warwickshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Corsham., 1 (Box 3)
      - Corsham Court., 2 (Box 3)
      - Cowdray, Sussex., 1 (Box 3)
      - Craigievar Castle, Scotland., 1 (Box 3)
      - Cranborne Manor House, Dorset., 1 (Box 3)
      - Culzean Castle., 3 (Box 3)
      - Denham Place, Buckinghamshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Ditchley., 4 (Box 3)
      - Dorfold Hall, Cheshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Durham., 1 (Box 3)
      - Edzell Castle, near Brechin, Scotland., 1 (Box 3)
      - Elkins., 1 (Box 3)
      - Essex., 1 (Box 3)
      - Florence Court., 1 (Box 3)
      - Ford House, Devonshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Foremarke Hall, near Repton, Derbyshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Fountains Hall, Yorkshire., 1 (Box 3)
      - Glin Castle., 3 (Box 3)
      - Guildford., 2 (Box 4)
      - Hagley Park., 4 (Box 4)
      - Hailsham, Sussex., 1 (Box 4)
      - Harewood House., 1 (Box 4)
      - Haslemere., 1 (Box 4)
      - Hatch Court, Somerset., 1 (Box 4)
      - Hawarden Castle., 1 (Box 4)
      - Heaton Park, Lancashire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Hengrave Hall, Suffolk., 1 (Box 4)
      - Hever Castle, Kent., 1 (Box 4)
      - Hogton Tower., 1 (Box 4)
      - Holland House., 1 (Box 4)
      - Houghton Hall., 3 (Box 4)
      - Huntingdon., 1 (Box 4)
      - Ickworth, Suffolk., 3 (Box 4)
      - Kenwood., 1 (Box 4)
      - Kew, Surrey., 5 (Box 4)
      - Kimbolton Castle, Huntingdon., 1 (Box 4)
      - Ki ngs Lynn., 1 (Box 4)
      - Knebworth, Hertfordshire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Lacock., 1 (Box 4)
      - Leixlip Castle., 1 (Box 4)
      - Lindfield., 2 (Box 4)
      - Liverpool, 1 (Box 4)
      - Llanerchaern, Cardiganshire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Longleat, Wiltshire., 2 (Box 4)
      - Luscombe Castle., 2 (Box 4)
      - Mells, Somerset., 1 (Box 4)
      - Milton Abbas., 2 (Box 4)
      - Mount Stewart., 1 (Box 4)
      - Moyns Park, Essex., 1 (Box 4)
      - Northampton., 1 (Box 4)
      - Nonesuch Palace., 1 (Box 4)
      - Otham, near Maidstone., 1 (Box 4)
      - Pain's Hill., 1 (Box 4)
      - Parham., 1 (Box 4)
      - Pondisford Park., 1 (Box 4)
      - Rickmansworth., 1 (Box 4)
      - Rousham., 2 (Box 4)
      - Russborough., 1 (Box 4)
      - Saltram House, Devon., 2 (Box 4)
      - Sawston Hall, Cambridgeshire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Shandon, County Cork, Ireland., 1 (Box 4)
      - Sherborne Lodge, Dorset., 1 (Box 4)
      - Slane Castle., 2 (Box 4)
      - Southampton., 1 (Box 4)
      - Stanton, Gloucestershire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Stapleford Park., 1 (Box 4)
      - Steeple Bumpstead, Essex., 1 (Box 4)
      - Stockeld Park, Yorkshire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Sutton Bonington., 1 (Box 4)
      - Temple Dinsley, Hertfordshire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Trent House, Somersetshire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Twickenham., 2 (Box 4)
      - Virginia Water., 1 (Box 4)
      - Wellington College., 1 (Box 4)
      - Westwood Park, Worcestershire., 1 (Box 4)
      - West Wycombe., 5 (Box 4)
      - Wimpole Hall, Cambridgeshire., 4 (Box 4)
      - Winchester., 1 (Box 4)
      - Winslow Hall, Buckinghamshire., 1 (Box 4)
      - Woburn., 1 (Box 4)
      - Wollaton Hall., 3 (Box 5)
    - Individual locations., 730 (Box 5)
      - Bath., 14 (Box 5)
      - Birmingham., 4 (Box 5)
      - Blenheim, Woodstock, Oxfordshire., 26 (Box 5)
      - Blickling Hall, Aylsham, Norfolk., 4 (Box 5)
      - Bowood, Wiltshire., 6 (Box 5)
      - Burghley House., 3 (Box 5)
      - Cambridge., 22 (Box 5)
        - Senate House., 4 (Box 5)
        - University., 18 (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous buildings., 5 (Box 5)
          - Caius College., 5 (Box 5)
          - Pembroke College Chapel., 2 (Box 6)
          - Trinity College., 6 (Box 6)
      - Castle Howard, Yorkshire., 40 (Box 6)
      - Charlcote, Warwickshire., 3 (Box 6)
      - Chatsworth, Derbyshire., 9 (Box 6)
      - Chiswick House, Middlesex., 16 (Box 7)
      - Cobham Hall, Kent., 3 (Box 7)
      - Dublin., 9 (Box 7)
      - Easton Neston, Northamptonshire., 7 (Box 7)
      - Edinburgh., 5 (Box 7)
      - Greenwich., 43 (Box 7)
        - Miscellaneous buildings., 9 (Box 7)
        - Hospitals., 34 (Box 8)
      - Guy's Cliff., 4 (Box 8)
      - Haddon Hall, Derbyshire., 9 (Box 8)
      - Ham House, Surrey., 7 (Box 8)
      - Hampton Court., 17 (Box 8)
      - Hardwick Hall, Derbyshire., 5 (Box 8)
      - Hatfield House., 7 (Box 8)
      - Heveningham Hall, Suffolk., 3 (Box 8)
      - Holkham Hall., 5 (Box 8)
      - Ightham Mote, Kent., 4 (Box 8)
      - Kedleston Hall, Derbyshire., 8 (Box 9)
      - Kirby Hall., 11 (Box 9)
      - Knole Hall, Sevenoaks, Kent., 6 (Box 9)
      - Little Moreton Hall, Cheshire., 3 (Box 9)
      - Llangollen, Wales., 4 (Box 9)
      - London., 239 (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous buildings, views, monuments, and plans., 15 (Box 9)
        - Churches., 124 (Box 9)
          - Miscellaneous churches., 29 (Box 10)
          - Christ Church, Spitalfields., 3 (Box 10)
          - Saint Bride's., 3 (Box 10)
          - Saint George-in-the-East., 5 (Box 10)
          - Saint Lawrence Jewry., 3 (Box 10)
          - Saint Martin's-in-the-Fields., 5 (Box 10)
          - Saint Mary-le-Bow., 8 (Box 10)
          - Saint Mary Woolnoth., 3 (Box 10)
          - Saint Paul's Cathedral., 52 (Box 10)
            - Plans, sections and models., 15 (Box 10)
            - Exterior., 15 (Box 10)
            - Interior., 22 (Box 11)
          - Saint Stephen, Walbrook., 13 (Box 11)
        - Clubs., 4 (Box 11)
        - Government buildings., 23 (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous buildings., 4 (Box 11)
          - Horse Guards., 5 (Box 11)
          - Somerset House., 14 (Box 11)
        - Hospitals., 15 (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous buildings., 1 (Box 11)
          - Chelsea Royal Hospital., 14 (Box 11)
        - Houses., 28 (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous houses., 21 (Box 11)
          - 20 Saint James Square., 7 (Box 12)
        - Inns and hotels., 7 (Box 12)
        - Palaces., 23 (Box 12)
          - Miscellaneous palaces., 1 (Box 12)
          - Whitehall., 22 (Box 12)
            - Miscellaneous information., 1 (Box 12)
            - Proposed plans., 15 (Box 12)
            - Exterior., 6 (Box 12)
      - Longford Castle., 2 (Box 12)
      - Longleat., 3 (Box 12)
      - Luton Park, Bedfordshire., 4 (Box 12)
      - Mereworth, Kent., 6 (Box 12)
      - Montacute, Somerset., 15 (Box 13)
      - Osterley Park, Middlesex., 27 (Box 13)
        - Exterior., 8 (Box 13)
        - Interior., 19 (Box 13)
      - Oxford., 34 (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous buildings and views., 19 (Box 13)
        - Christ Church College., 6 (Box 13)
        - Queen's College., 7 (Box 13)
        - Radcliffe Camera., 2 (Box 13)
      - Penshurst Place, Kent., 4 (Box 13)
      - Powerscourt, Ireland., 3 (Box 14)
      - Raynham, Norfolk., 2 (Box 14)
      - Rowsley, Derbyshire., 3 (Box 14)
      - Rushton Hall, Northamptonshire., 3 (Box 14)
      - Salisbury., 3 (Box 14)
      - Seaton Delaval., 6 (Box 14)
      - South Wraxall, Wiltshire., 4 (Box 14)
      - Stourhead., 7 (Box 14)
      - Stowe., 20 (Box 14)
        - Miscellaneous buildings, plans and views., 10 (Box 14)
        - Temples., 10 (Box 14)
      - Strawberry Hill., 3 (Box 14)
      - Syon House, Middlesex., 10 (Box 14)
      - The Vyne, Hampshire., 6 (Box 14)
      - Wilton., 8 (Box 15)
      - Windsor., 5 (Box 15)
      - Wollaton Hall, Nottinghamshire., 3 (Box 15)
      - York., 3 (Box 15)
  - Czechoslovakia., 7 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 1 (Box 15)
      - Ossegg (Osek)., 1 (Box 15)
    - Individual locations., 6 (Box 15)
      - Prague., 6 (Box 15)
  - Denmark., 24 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 15 (Box 15)
      - Brons., 1 (Box 15)
      - Fredensborg., 3 (Box 15)
      - Frederiksborg., 2 (Box 15)
      - Hillerod., 1 (Box 15)
      - Klampenborg., 1 (Box 15)
      - Kronberg., 1 (Box 15)
      - Mons., 3 (Box 15)
      - Roskilde., 4 (Box 15)
    - Individual locations., 9 (Box 15)
      - Copenhagen., 9 (Box 15)